Guide to the John Ewart Wallace Sterling, Chancellor of Stanford University, Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Papers, Series 1
  - Stanford University
    - Board of Trustees.
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1978 Sept 12 (Box 44B, Folder 6)
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1978 Oct 10 (Box 44B, Folder 7)
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1978 Nov 14 (Box 44B, Folder 8)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1983 Sept. 13 (Box 45A, Folder 1)
      - Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1983 June 10 (Box 45A, Folder 2)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1983 June 10 (Box 45A, Folder 3)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1983 May 10 (Box 45A, Folder 4)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustee, 1983 March 8 (Box 45A, Folder 5)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1983 May 10 (Box 45A, Folder 6)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1983 Feb. 8 (Box 45A, Folder 7)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1983 March 8 (Box 45A, Folder 8)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1983 Feb. 8 (Box 45A, Folder 9)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1982 Dec. 14 (Box 45A, Folder 10)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1982 Dec. 14 (Box 45A, Folder 11)
      - Report of the Organization and Management Study Group, 1982 Dec. 1 (Box 45A, Folder 12)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1982 Oct. 12 (Box 45A, Folder 13)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1982 Oct. 12 (Box 45A, Folder 14)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1982 Sept. 14 (Box 45A, Folder 15)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1982 Sept. 14 (Box 45A, Folder 16)
      - Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1982 June 11 (Box 45A, Folder 17)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1982 June 11 (Box 45A, Folder 18)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1982 May 11 (Box 45A, Folder 19)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1982 May 11 (Box 45A, Folder 20)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1982 March 9 (Box 45A, Folder 21)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1982 March 9 (Box 45A, Folder 22)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1982 Feb. 9 (Box 45A, Folder 23)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1982 Feb. 9 (Box 45A, Folder 24)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1982 Dec. 8 (Box 45A, Folder 25)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1981 Dec. 8 (Box 45A, Folder 26)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1981 Oct. 13 (Box 45A, Folder 27)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1981 Sept. 15 (Box 45A, Folder 28)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1981 June 12 (Box 45A, Folder 29)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1981 May 12 (Box 45A, Folder 30)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1981 March 10 (Box 45A, Folder 31)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1981 Feb. 10 (Box 45A, Folder 32)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1980 Dec. 9 (Box 45A, Folder 33)
      - Stanford Land Use Plan Draft, 1980 (Box 45A, Folder 34)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1980 Oct. 14 (Box 45A, Folder 35)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1980 Sept. 9 (Box 45A, Folder 36)
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1980 June 13 (Box 45B, Folder 1)
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1980 April 8 (Box 45B, Folder 2)
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1980 March 11 (Box 45B, Folder 3)
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1980 February 12 (Box 45B, Folder 4)
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1979 December 11 (Box 45B, Folder 5)
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1979 October 9 (Box 45B, Folder 6)
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1979 September 11 (Box 45B, Folder 7)
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1979 June 15 (Box 45B, Folder 8)
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1979 May 8 (Box 45B, Folder 9)
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1979 April 8-9 (Box 45B, Folder 10)
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1979 March 12-13 (Box 45B, Folder 11)
      - Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting Agenda, 1979 February 13 (Box 45B, Folder 12)
      - Minutes of the Annual Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1985 June 14 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1985 May 14 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1985 June 14 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1985 May 14 (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1985 March 12 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1985 March 12 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - Operating Budget Guidelines, 1985-1986 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1985 Feb. 12 (Box 46, Folder 8)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1985 Feb. 12 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - Letter from Kennedy to Board of Trustees and Treasury Department's Tax Proposals, 1984 Dec. - 1985 Jan. (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - Minutes of the regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1984 Dec. 11 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - Executive Summary: Debt at Stanford, 1984 Dec. (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1984 Dec. 11 (Box 46, Folder 13)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1984 Oct. 9 (Box 46, Folder 14)
      - Letter from Kennedy and Rosse to Board of Trustee, 1984 Sept. 26 (Box 46, Folder 15)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1984 Oct. 9 (Box 46, Folder 16)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1984 Sept. 9 (Box 46, Folder 17)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1984 Sept. 9 (Box 46, Folder 18)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1984 June 15 (Box 46, Folder 19)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1984 June 15 (Box 46, Folder 20)
      - Meeting of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1984 May 8 (Box 46, Folder 21)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1984 May 8 (Box 46, Folder 22)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1984 March 13 (Box 46, Folder 23)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1984 March 13 (Box 46, Folder 24)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1984 Feb. 14 (Box 46, Folder 25)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1984 Feb. 14 (Box 46, Folder 26)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1983 Dec. 13 (Box 46, Folder 27)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1983 Dec. 13 (Box 46, Folder 28)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1983 Oct. 11 (Box 46, Folder 29)
      - Agenda (Stanford University Board of Trustees Meeting), 1983 Oct. 11 (Box 46, Folder 30)
      - Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1983 Sept. 13 (Box 46, Folder 31)
      - Stanford University Securities Portfolio, 1975 Aug. 31 (Box 46, Folder 32)
      - Board of Trustees Meeting Personnel Guide, 1975-1976 (Box 46, Folder 33)
      - Letter from Massy to Board of Trustees, 1982 April 27 (Box 46, Folder 34)
      - Stanford University Staff Paper Stanford Housing Program, 1982 May (Box 46, Folder 35)
      - Additional Matters, 1982 Sept. 14 (Box 46, Folder 36)
      - Action of the Board of Trustees, By-Laws of the Board of Trustees, 1982 May 11 (Box 46, Folder 37)
      - Additional Matters, 1982 June 11 (Box 46, Folder 38)
      - Additional Matters, 1982 Oct. 12 (Box 46, Folder 39)
      - Gift Procurement: Volunteer Organization, Minutes Trustees Re Campaign, Cabinet, 1970-1971 (Box 46, Folder 40)
  - Speeches
    - Place of The Med. Sch. In the Univ (Toronto), 1958 Aug. 29 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Report to the Board of Trustees, 1958 July 17 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Opening of The Stanford-In-Germany, 1958 June 24 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Stanford Commencement, 1958 June 15 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Statement to the Academic Council, 1958 June 13 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Cate School Commencement, 1958 June 7 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Dinner for Scientists & Mathematicians, 1958 May 26 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - UBS Congregation Exercises, 1958 May 20 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Alumni conference - Jews, 1958 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Mothers Club of Southern California, 1958 May 8 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Inauguration of Dro Glenn S. Dumke, President San Francisco State College, 1958 May 2 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - San Francisco Advertising Club, 1958 April 23 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Founder's Day, 1958 March 9 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - CBS TV Show "The Great Challenge", 1958 Feb. 23 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Speech - Bd. of Gov. Stanford Assoc., 1958 Feb. 14 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Boy Scouts, San Mateo Area Council, 1958 Jan. 9 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Amer. Iron & Steel Institute, 1957 Nov. 8 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Stanford Faculty Club, 1957 Nov. 1 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - H. Hoover & His Workshop for Peace, 1957 Oct. 31 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - International Industrial Development Conference, 1957 Oct. 18 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - Parent's Day, 1957 Oct. 12 (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - Parent's Committee, 1957 Oct. 7 (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - Stanford Associates, BD. of Gov., 1957 Sept. 28 (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - Freshman Convocation, 1957 Sept. 18 (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - Speech-Commencement 1957, 1957 June 16 (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - Speeches - Alumni Circuit (conferences), 1957 (Box 38, Folder 26)
    - Station KZSU, 1957 May 14 (Box 38, Folder 27)
    - San Jose State College Centennial, 1957 May 2 (Box 38, Folder 28)
    - Mother's Club, 1957 April 16 (Box 38, Folder 29)
    - Dean of Women's Convention, S.F., 1957 March 30 (Box 38, Folder 30)
    - Diocese of Olympia, Seattle, Wn. Bishop Stephen F. Bayne, Jr., 1957 March 26 (Box 38, Folder 31)
    - Speeches - Dr. Rogers' Dinner, 1957 Feb. 9 (Box 38, Folder 32)
    - Med. Sch. Center Campaign-Press Luncheon, 1957 Feb. 7 (Box 38, Folder 33)
    - Speech-Women's Faculty Club, 1957 Feb. 11 (Box 38, Folder 34)
    - Medical Center Fund Luncheon, 1956 Nov. 26 (Box 38, Folder 35)
    - Junior League of San Francisco, 1956 Nov. 20 (Box 38, Folder 36)
    - Parent's Day, 1956 Oct. 13 (Box 38, Folder 37)
    - Freshman Convocation, 1956 Sept. 19 (Box 38, Folder 38)
    - Commencement 1956, 1956 June 17 (Box 38, Folder 39)
    - "Fathers and Sons" Menlo College, 1956 June 8 (Box 38, Folder 40)
    - Alumni Conference of Campus, 1956 May 19 (Box 38, Folder 41)
    - Alumni Clubs & Conferences, 1956 (Box 38, Folder 42)
    - Univ. of Hawaii Library Dedication, 1956 May 4 (Box 38, Folder 43)
    - Business Deans Dinner, 1956 April 27 (Box 38, Folder 44)
    - Speech-Board of Governors Dinner, 1956 Feb. 24 (Box 38, Folder 45)
    - Andover Alumni Dinner - Los Angeles, 1956 Feb. 7 (Box 38, Folder 46)
    - Tuesday Evening Series (record), 1956 Jan. 10 (Box 38, Folder 47)
    - "No Man is an Island" Federation of Jewish Charities, 1955 Dec. 20 (Box 38, Folder 48)
    - "Education is Everbody's Business" American Petroleum Institute, 1955 Nov. 14 (Box 38, Folder 49)
    - Parents Day, 1955 Nov. 12 (Box 38, Folder 50)
    - Speech - Committees of Educational Inquiry, 1955 Oct. 21 (Box 38, Folder 51)
    - Mothers' Club, 1955 Oct. 18 (Box 38, Folder 52)
    - Sterling Position on Fraternities, 1955 Oct. 6 (Box 38, Folder 53)
    - Fund Volunteers Kick-Off, 1955 Oct. 6 (Box 38, Folder 54)
    - Parents Committee, 1955 Oct. 6 (Box 38, Folder 55)
    - AWS Leadership Day Program, 1955 Sept. 23 (Box 38, Folder 56)
    - Freshman Convocation, 1955 Sept. 22 (Box 38, Folder 57)
    - Stanford Assicates Board of Governors, 1955 Sept. 17 (Box 38, Folder 58)
    - "Education is Everbody's Business" Investment Bankers Assn. Santa Barbara Convention, 1955 June 28 (Box 38, Folder 59)
    - Commencement, 1955 June 19 (Box 38, Folder 60)
    - Speech - Los Angleles Dinner "John Bull and Uncle Sam at College.", 1955 June 9 (Box 38, Folder 61)
    - Speech - Corporate Luncheon, S.F. (General Secretary file), 1955 June 7 (Box 38, Folder 62)
    - Speech - Inauguration of Willis M. Tate, So. Methodist Univ., 1955 May 5 (Box 38, Folder 63)
    - Founders' Day, 1955 March 6 (Box 38, Folder 64)
    - Y.W.C.A. Speech, 1955 Feb. 25 (Box 38, Folder 65)
    - Reno Alumni Speech, 1955 Feb. 5 (Box 38, Folder 66)
    - Salt Lake City Alumni Speech, 1955 Feb. (Box 38, Folder 67)
    - Mothers' Club, 1955 Jan. 18 (Box 38, Folder 68)
    - Memorial Service for Gerorge Pierce, 1954 Oct. 19 (Box 38, Folder 69)
    - "Back to the Farm Week" Frost Amphitheatre, 1954 Oct. 6 (Box 38, Folder 70)
    - Freshmen Assembly, 1954 Sept. 23 (Box 38, Folder 71)
    - Bond Club, San Francisco, 1954 Sept. 22 (Box 38, Folder 72)
    - Jackling Statue Dedication Salt Lake City, 1954 Aug. 14 (Box 38, Folder 73)
    - Commencement, 1954 June 13 (Box 38, Folder 74)
    - "The Blind Men and the Elephant" Rice Institute, 1954 June (Box 38, Folder 75)
    - Dr. Sterling's Intoduction at Jacks Lecture, 1954 April 30 (Box 38, Folder 76)
    - Stanford Mother's Club of Portland, 1954 April 26 (Box 38, Folder 77)
    - Western College Assoc., 1954 April 9 (Box 38, Folder 78)
    - Introduction of Carlton J. H. Hayes Raymond Fred West Lecture, 1954 April 5 (Box 38, Folder 79)
    - Dr. Sterling Preface to Cutler Book, 1954 March 27 (Box 38, Folder 80)
    - Alumni Conference Los Angeles, 1954 March 21 (Box 38, Folder 81)
    - Founders' Day, 1954 March 7 (Box 38, Folder 82)
    - Mothers' Club, 1954 Jan. 19 (Box 38, Folder 83)
    - Twilight Club David Starr Jordan, 1954 Jan. (Box 38, Folder 84)
    - "Fathers and Sons" Boy Scouts Honor Dinner, 1953 Oct. 19 (Box 38, Folder 85)
    - "Discipline of Freedom" Insurance Luncheon, San Francisco, 1953 Oct. 6 (Box 38, Folder 86)
    - Luncheon for Prince Akihito San Francisco, 1953 Oct. 2 (Box 38, Folder 87)
    - Loren Chandler Dinner, 1953 Sept. 25 (Box 38, Folder 88)
    - Leadership Day Program, 1953 Sept. 25 (Box 38, Folder 89)
    - American Institute of Banking, 1953 June 24 (Box 38, Folder 90)
    - Freshman Assembly, 1953 Sept. 24 (Box 38, Folder 91)
    - Greetings to Freshmen Stanford Daily, 1953 (Box 38, Folder 92)
    - Speech-Castilleja School "Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star.", 1953 June 9 (Box 38, Folder 93)
    - Speech - Alumni Day Campus, 1953 (Box 38, Folder 94)
    - Achievement Day Award, 1953 May 22 (Box 38, Folder 95)
    - National Paperboard Association, 1953 May 19 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Speech Children's Home Society of California, 1953 May 14 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Inauguration of Clark Kerr as Chancellor, U.C. Berkeley, 1953 March 23 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Founders' Day, 1953 March 8 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Speech - San Deigo Alumni Conf., 1953 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - "Defense of Freedom" Ad. Club (S.F.), 1953 Feb. 25 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Mothers' Club, 1953 Jan. 20 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Sunset Club, 1952 Dec. (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Student Assembly, 1952 Dec. 2 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "Education is Your Business" Stock Exchange, 1952 Oct. 6 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Student Assembly Frost Amphitheatre, 1952 Oct. 2 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Freshman Assembly, 1952 Sept. 25 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - O, Say Can You See? Amer. Inst. of Bank, 1952 Aug. 26 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Commencement, 1952 June 15 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Speech - Could You and I with Fate Conspire Commencement-Fresno State College, 1952 June 10 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Speech - Commencement - Katherine Branson's School, 1952 June 5 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Speech - Education: Blind Men & Elephant Stanford Education Club, S.F., 1952 May 8 (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - "World Leadership - Supply and Demand" Alumni Homecoming, 1952 May 3 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Speech - Country Club or College Student Election Assembly, 1952 April 28 (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Association of American Universities, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - Stanford A.A.U.P., 1952 March 13 (Box 39, Folder 21)
    - Founders' Day, 1952 March 9 (Box 39, Folder 22)
    - J.C. Penney Company, 1952 March 7 (Box 39, Folder 23)
    - Speech - Educ. Pub. Relations American College Public Relations Ass., 1952 Feb. 2 (Box 39, Folder 24)
    - Stanford Associates San Francisco/ Los Angeles, 1952 Jan. 25, 29 (Box 39, Folder 25)
    - Dedication of Memorial Plaques Memorial Auditorium, 1952 Jan. 27 (Box 39, Folder 26)
    - Mothers' Club, 1952 Jan. 15 (Box 39, Folder 27)
    - Bohemian Club, 1951 Dec. 13 (Box 39, Folder 28)
    - "The Integrity of the University" Univ. of Chicago Round Table, 1951 Oct. 21 (Box 39, Folder 29)
    - "Disciplines of Freedom" Inauguration of Chan. Kimpton, 1951 Oct. 18 (Box 39, Folder 30)
    - Greetings to Freshmen, 1951 (Box 39, Folder 31)
    - Greetings to the Class Commencement, 1951 June 18 (Box 39, Folder 32)
    - "The Impact of Science on Education", 1951 June (Box 39, Folder 33)
    - Miss Burke's School for Girls Commencement, 1951 June (Box 39, Folder 34)
    - "Getting and Education" Student Assembly, 1951 May 18 (Box 39, Folder 35)
    - "Student Self Government" Student Assembly, 1951 April 23 (Box 39, Folder 36)
    - "Poor George" Santa Clara Univ. Centennial, 1951 April 11 (Box 39, Folder 37)
    - Los Angeles Alumni Conference, 1951 March (Box 39, Folder 38)
    - R-Planners and Associates Dinner, 1951 Jan. 19 (Box 39, Folder 39)
    - Public Education Society of San Francisco, 1950 Dec. 18 (Box 39, Folder 40)
    - Model General Assembly of United Nations Greetings, 1950 (Box 39, Folder 41)
    - Alumni Group Meetings, 1950 (Box 39, Folder 42)
    - "Opportunity and Response" Founders Day, 1950 March 9 (Box 39, Folder 43)
    - "A Century in Retrospect" Huntington Library Founders Day, 1950 Feb. 27 (Box 39, Folder 44)
    - "A Lofty Purpose Shared" Inaugural Address, 1949 Oct. 7 (Box 39, Folder 45)
    - Greetings to Freshmen, 1949 Sept. 23 (Box 39, Folder 46)
    - "Town Hall" Program, 1949 Sept. 9 (Box 39, Folder 47)
    - Herbert Hoover Seventy-Fifth Birthday, 1949 Aug. 10 (Box 39, Folder 48)
    - "Changes and Chances" Commencement, 1949 June 19 (Box 39, Folder 49)
    - Could You and I with Fate Conspire" Pomona Commencement, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 50)
    - Commonwealth Club, 1949 May 27 (Box 39, Folder 51)
    - Alumni Conference, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 52)
    - Fraternity Group, 1949 May 5 (Box 39, Folder 53)
    - Stanford Associates Los Angeles, 1949 April 26 (Box 39, Folder 54)
    - Easter Sunrise Service, 1949 April 17 (Box 39, Folder 55)
    - Stanford Associates San Francisco, 1949 April 12 (Box 39, Folder 56)
    - Traditions Day Rally, 1949 April 7 (Box 39, Folder 57)
    - Academic Council, 1949 April 6 (Box 39, Folder 58)
    - "Volts, Vectors, and Votes" Cal tech Froosh Camp, 1948 (Box 39, Folder 59)
    - "The Adventure of the Diver" Occidental College Commencement Address, 1948 June 14 (Box 39, Folder 60)
    - "Where Do We Go From Here?" Beverly Hills Forum, 1947 June 3 (Box 39, Folder 61)
    - "What is this Thing Called Welfare?", undated (Box 39, Folder 62)
    - Speech Materials Miscellaneous, 1957-1973 (Box 39, Folder 63)
    - A, 1955-1966 (Box 39, Folder 64)
    - B, 1960-1966 (Box 39, Folder 65)
    - C, 1955-1966 (Box 39, Folder 66)
    - D, 1955-1972 (Box 39, Folder 67)
    - E, 1955, 1966, 1972 (Box 39, Folder 68)
    - F, 1955-1956, 1964 (Box 39, Folder 69)
    - G, 1955-1973 (Box 39, Folder 70)
    - H, 1952-1969 (Box 39, Folder 71)
    - I, undated (Box 39, Folder 72)
    - J, 1958, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 73)
    - K, 1955, 1965-1967 (Box 39, Folder 74)
    - L, 1955-1960 (Box 39, Folder 75)
    - M, 1956-1966 (Box 39, Folder 76)
    - N, 1954-1965 (Box 39, Folder 77)
    - O, 1955-1965 (Box 39, Folder 78)
    - P, 1955-1966 (Box 39, Folder 79)
    - Q, undated (Box 39, Folder 80)
    - Quotations, 1953, 1961-1967 (Box 39, Folder 81)
    - R, 1954-1966 (Box 39, Folder 82)
    - S, 1957-1966 (Box 39, Folder 83)
    - T, 1955-1968 (Box 39, Folder 84)
    - U, 1956 (Box 39, Folder 85)
    - V, undated (Box 39, Folder 86)
    - W, 1950, 1956, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 87)
    - X-Y-Z, 1956 (Box 39, Folder 88)
  - Objects
    - Naming of J.E. Wallace Sterling Library of Landscape Architecture, White House Order, Letter to Carol, 1985 July, Nov. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Lampada Ferens Plaque, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Los Angeles Coliseum Youth Eternal First Senior Olympics Marble Trophy, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Plaque from Sam Curran, Strathelyde University, June 11 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Plaque from Eugene M. Farber, 1974 Dec. 3 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Commemorating Pacific Telephone's 500,000th Telephone in Santa Clara County, 1966 May 12 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Decorative Container: With Compliments of Mr. Khalid Waiieed Ferozsons Laboratories Nowshera (W. Pakistan), undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - J.E. Wallace Sterling, President Stanford University Stanford Conference in Hawaii, Princess Kaiulani Hotel (Wooden Mortar and Pestle), 1963 March 23 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - The World at Your Doorstep, San Francisco Examiner (Glass Plate), undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Papers, Series 2
  - Vice Chancellors, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1st Copy of Award, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Greetings of the Season, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Russian Historical Archive and Repository, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Harold F. McGuire (deceased 12/1/81), 1978-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fred H. Merrill (deceased 1/9/81), 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - H. Pearson Gundy, 1961-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ernest W. McFarland, 1971-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - McFarland State Park, 1975-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Tex" Middleton", 1972-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - R. Ellsworth Miller, 1969-1970, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pictures, 1949-1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Publicity, 1951-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Rad Robinson, 1954-1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The San Francisco Foundation, 1973-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Scottish Development Agency, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Stanford Observer Article, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - J.E. Wallace Sterling Award Stanford Alumni Association, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - J.E. Wallace Sterling Distinguished Medical Alumnus Award, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Robert C. Swain, 1973-1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - University Seminars Spring 1980, 1980 Jan.-May (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Ray Lyman Wilbur, 1941-1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Notes found in Dr. Sterling's Desk, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - London File, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - More Trustees Info, 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Death Notices (A-2 Files), 1971-1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - For General Files, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)